<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal</title>
    <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:19:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugo.gavriliu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waste Collection Schedule in HomeAssistant</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/waste-collection-schedule-in-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:19:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/waste-collection-schedule-in-ha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; forget to take out the garbage bins. And around here, the rule is simple: if your bins aren’t on the sidewalk, the garbage truck just cruises by like a VIP limo ignoring peasants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we first moved in, I forgot to take out the recycling bags (Gelber Sack) three times in a row. This resulted in a majestic mountain of 25 bags filled with plastic, empty cat food cans, and my dignity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containers Not Mounting Longhorn Volumes</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/containers-not-mounting-longhorn-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:34:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/containers-not-mounting-longhorn-volumes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoutout to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/derekbit&#34;&gt;derekbit&lt;/a&gt; for saving my cluster from a tragic post-power-outage existential crisis. My entire homelab went down for a few hours, and Longhorn wasn’t exactly in a hurry to come back. More details on the saga can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/longhorn/longhorn/issues/7183&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in this lifesaving &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/longhorn/longhorn/issues/7183#issuecomment-1823715359&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-used&#34;&gt;Tools used&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stern/stern&#34;&gt;stern&lt;/a&gt;: Stern allows you to &lt;code&gt;tail&lt;/code&gt; multiple pods on Kubernetes and multiple containers within the pod. Each result is color coded for quicker debugging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-the-logs&#34;&gt;Check the logs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start questioning your life choices, run:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combine Helm and K8s Manifests in One ArgoCD Application</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/argocd-combine-helm-and-k8s-manifests-in-one-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 18:34:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/argocd-combine-helm-and-k8s-manifests-in-one-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel pretty dumb right now. I used 2 ArgoCD applications for the same thing—one for my Helm chart, the other for flat manifest YAML files. Apparently, thinking isn’t my strong suit. I mean, I could barely remember where I put my coffee, let alone plan a proper ArgoCD setup! So, like any reasonable person, I had to RTFM (read the fine manual, of course), and eventually stumbled upon the brilliant solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:35:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started this blog because I figured it’s time to share my knowledge and opinions with the world. After all, if it’s on the internet, it must be true… right? Well, apparently not. There’s a ton of outdated info and some outright nonsense out there. Even ChatGPT has its off days—sometimes the info is ancient, and other times it just hits me with the classic ‘You’re right!’ like I’m talking to a cheerleader instead of getting actual answers. So here I am, doing my part to make the internet a little less… well, internet-y!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to seal and unseal secrets with Bitnami Sealed-Secrets</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/how-to-seal-and-unseal-secrets-with-bitnami-sealed-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:41:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/posts/how-to-seal-and-unseal-secrets-with-bitnami-sealed-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to push my Kubernetes manifests to GitHub because running Git locally on the same k3s cluster as ArgoCD seemed like asking for trouble. I mean, what happens if something goes wrong? Suddenly, you’re locked out of your repository, and your applications just sit there looking sad, like ‘Hey, I need a home!’ Pushing everything - including secrets — straight to GitHub? That’s like sending your passwords in a postcard: ‘Hey, here’s all my private stuff for the world to see!’ So, I decided to use Bitnami’s Sealed Secrets. At least now, my secrets are sealed tighter than my New Year’s resolution to work out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo.gavriliu.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;homelab&#34;&gt;Homelab&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My homelab is running on 4 Intel NUCs, all happily chugging along with k3s. The network backbone is a UniFi setup, featuring a UDMPro and a UniFi Switch 24 Pro POE. Right now, it’s a cozy 1GB network, but I’m planning to bump it up to 2.5GB soon—because, well, who doesn’t love faster speeds? The only thing slowing me down at the moment is the backup process—Longhorn and Kasten.io backups are giving me a bit of a bottleneck, with everything stored safely on my trusty old Synology DS918+.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
